<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on The imposter syndrome</title>
    <link>https://www.theimpostersyndrome.dev/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on The imposter syndrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.theimpostersyndrome.dev/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sherlock &#39;otool&#39; Holmes</title>
      <link>https://www.theimpostersyndrome.dev/posts/solving_dynamic_linking_problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.theimpostersyndrome.dev/posts/solving_dynamic_linking_problems/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever had the feeling that something really magic has happened to your computer because of a thing that was working suddenly, out of nowhere, stopped working? Wait, maybe I made some changes, let’s go back to master&amp;hellip; mmh no&amp;hellip; it isn’t working anymore… but how? This code is working on other machines! It worked on mine like 20 minutes ago! This is impossible, nothing changed and it is not working anymore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To SQL or to NoSQL?</title>
      <link>https://www.theimpostersyndrome.dev/posts/to_sql_or_to_nosql/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.theimpostersyndrome.dev/posts/to_sql_or_to_nosql/</guid>
      <description>To SQL or to NoSQL? Is that the real question? Nah, the real war out there is to agree on how to pronounce it. Do you pronounce it “Ess-cue-ell” or maybe you pronounce it “sequel” like Bill Gates among others? If you want to know how I pronounce it… I use both just to bother people.
Jokes aside, let’s get on this post! Would you like to know the differences between these two database models?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Packaging adventures volume III: Wix</title>
      <link>https://www.theimpostersyndrome.dev/posts/windowswixpackaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.theimpostersyndrome.dev/posts/windowswixpackaging/</guid>
      <description>Third and final chapter of the packaging adventures. The previous post about Windows packaging was posted a couple of months ago and we learned how to create a simple Windows installer thanks to a Visual Studio extension. If you remember properly, there were some inconvenient like having two different installers (an MSI file for the app and an EXE file for the setup installer with the required extra components for our application).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing user stories</title>
      <link>https://www.theimpostersyndrome.dev/posts/developing_user_stories/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.theimpostersyndrome.dev/posts/developing_user_stories/</guid>
      <description>Last week, in a little meeting we usually do to close our SCRUM Sprint period of two weeks, I was showing all the new features I had developed for our product. One of the features was not accepted and therefore its related user story was moved back from &amp;ldquo;QA Review&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;On development&amp;rdquo; again. I misunderstood my task.
What can we do here? Should we just tell the developer what was wrong and wait for him to change it ASAP or maybe should we try to guess what led him to do it that way the first time to see if we have a problem in our product development workflow?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Packaging adventures volume II: Windows</title>
      <link>https://www.theimpostersyndrome.dev/posts/windowsuglypackaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.theimpostersyndrome.dev/posts/windowsuglypackaging/</guid>
      <description>So here we are with the second part of the packaging adventures. If you remember, we already talked about macOS packaging a few months ago and now it&amp;rsquo;s time to show you how to do it on Windows. Windows has many ways to package your applications and I am currently using another one for my production packages, but that will be explained in a third part of this packaging adventures. Let&amp;rsquo;s start with one of the most basic ways to achieve it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET Framework vs .NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.theimpostersyndrome.dev/posts/core_vs_framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.theimpostersyndrome.dev/posts/core_vs_framework/</guid>
      <description>First things first, I know I’ve been out for a couple of months without posting any article on my site. Sorry for that! I’ve been busy finishing up my computer science degree and I wanted to boost my final project by giving it my free time as much as possible. Thanks to that I have written down some Xamarin things to investigate and share them here, also. Now let’s get back to work!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET in a box</title>
      <link>https://www.theimpostersyndrome.dev/posts/dotnetinabox/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.theimpostersyndrome.dev/posts/dotnetinabox/</guid>
      <description>One of the most important things a .NET developer should know is what .NET is. It seems stupid but I know a lot of people that just starts coding and focusing in learning the .NET code they use. They can tell you why that .Count field is better than using the .Any () LINQ method to check for available values in your enumerator but they really don&amp;rsquo;t know (and some of them sadly don&amp;rsquo;t care) how their code is translated and optimized for a concrete processor in a concrete operating system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Packaging adventures volume I: macOS</title>
      <link>https://www.theimpostersyndrome.dev/posts/macospackaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.theimpostersyndrome.dev/posts/macospackaging/</guid>
      <description>If I had to define working (right) as a macOS developer out of the bounds of Xcode IDE with one expression I would do it as: &amp;ldquo;Oh, there is one more easy not easy thing Apple wants us to do to make it work properly&amp;rdquo;. Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been working and struggling hard with packaging the multiplatform application I work on. When Apple released macOS Catalina they introduced a lot of security changes and a lot of applications suddenly stopped working turning App Store outsider developers lifes in a little nightmare.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git survival kit</title>
      <link>https://www.theimpostersyndrome.dev/posts/git_survival_kit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.theimpostersyndrome.dev/posts/git_survival_kit/</guid>
      <description>When I first started in my current company I hadn&amp;rsquo;t used any version control system so when I started using Git it was a little tricky. Lucky me I had one of the best developers I&amp;rsquo;ve ever worked with, Víctor Guzmán. I remember he said something like: &amp;ldquo;Ok, you can use a GUI for a bad Git usage or you can use the Terminal for learning real Git usage. I use Terminal so I won&amp;rsquo;t help you with if you don&amp;rsquo;t use it&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m an imposter</title>
      <link>https://www.theimpostersyndrome.dev/posts/imposter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.theimpostersyndrome.dev/posts/imposter/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t know how I got here. I know I did not do the best technical test my company gave to me because I know I left that two or three very important things I considere basic so my test was incomplete. The job interview was not bad at all but I feel that my interviewer has interviewed better developers than I. Maybe they were running out of time and they needed the first mid-decent developer they could find or maybe they had not enough money to hire that better developer that I was talking about.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>